printo.in 2012-11-11

# Printo

Our Privacy Policy has been updated. Please read through the complete Privacy Policy.

Printo is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring you have a positive experience on our website. This policy outlines our personal information handling practices for both online and offline data. If you give us personal information, we will treat it according to this policy.

  * We encourage you to read this policy to ensure you understand Printoï¿½s privacy practices.
  * We adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:
  * We do not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to third parties for any purposes, including marketing purposes.
  * We do not share your contact information with another User without your explicit consent.
  * Any personally identifiable information that you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.
  * We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, or by means of a notice on our home page.

  *   *   *   * By continuing to use the Printo service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on the Printo website, you are consenting to the changes.
  * 

**  
1.Personal Information collected:**

Printo lets upload your photos and order personalized gifts for your friends and family online. _We advise you that if you do not wish to have this information used or displayed as described in the privacy policy and user agreement, you should reconsider becoming a member of the Printo community. You willingly provide us certain personal information, which we collect in order to allow you to benefit from the Printo services. If you have any hesitation about providing such information to us and/or having such information displayed on the Printo website or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, you should not become a member of the Printo community._

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

a. Registration: In order to become a User, you must first create an account on our website. To create an account you are required to provide information such as and including name, email address, country, date of birth, educational institutions you have attended, or organizations you have worked / working for, and a password chosen by you. You recognize and expressly acknowledge that this is personal information allowing others, including Printo, to identify you.

b. Photo Upload : As a member of the service provided by Printo, you are willingly, voluntarily and being fully aware of the sensitivities involved provide personally identifiable information and share your photos. You agree that your photos can have differing visibility option and you could set the options for each event, such as entirely private, partially public and public.

c. Log files, IP addresses and information about your computer

Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit the Printo web site we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave Printo. We also receive information such as, the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), type of web browser, referring site, date and time of your visit, name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the Printo service. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law.

d. Cookies and Web Beacons

Like most websites, Printo uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing User preferences and tracking User trends. In the course of serving advertisements or optimizing services to our Users, we may allow authorized third parties to place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Printo does not store personally identifiable information in the cookies.

We allow other companies, to serve advertisements to Users. These companies include third party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms. Printo may ï¿½targetï¿½ some ads to Users that fit a certain general profile. Printo does NOT use personally identifiable information to target ads.

e. Processing information about you and modification of such information

All the information you provide Printo, including sensitive personal information, is voluntary. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the User Agreement, but please note that your withdrawal of consent will not be retroactive.

You can access, modify, correct and eliminate the data about you which has been collected pursuant to your decision to become a User. If you update any of your information, we may keep a copy of the information which you originally provided to us in our archives for uses documented herein. We take your rights seriously and encourage you to use them if you deem this to be appropriate. You may exercise these rights by emailing us at privacy@printo.in.

f. External links.

This Privacy Policy applies to web sites and services that are owned and operated by Printo. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as search results or links from within our various services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you, for which Printo is not responsible or liable.

**2.Uses of Personal Information:**

Printoï¿½s online service which helps you connect with other Users or the public Printos. Your personally identifiable information you choose to provide on our website is used to help you describe yourself to other Users. Other information, that does not personally identify you as an individual, is collected by Printo from Users (such as, patterns of utilization described above) and is exclusively owned by Printo. This information can be utilized by Printo in such manner as Printo, in its sole discretion, deems appropriate.

a. Communication and Update

Printo will communicate with you through email and notices posted on the Printo website or through other means available through the service, including text and other forms of messaging. You can change your e-mail and contact preferences at any time by logging into your ï¿½ Accountï¿½ <http://www.printo.in/account/notifications> and change the account settings.

b. Sharing Information with Third Parties

Printo takes the privacy of Users very seriously. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes. We will only share your personally identifiable information with third parties to carry out your instructions or to provide specific services or information.

We may provide aggregated anonymous data about the usage of our services to third parties for such purposes as we deem, in our sole discretion, to be appropriate, including to prospective advertisers on Printo. If you wish to opt-out of this service, please email [support@printo.in](mailto:support@printo.in)

c. Surveys and Polls

As a User, you will receive requests to participate in market research including polls and surveys submitted by other Printo members. If you participate in surveys and polls offered through our website, the information you provide may be visible to others using the Printo website. You may opt-out of participating by changing your ï¿½Accountï¿½ [settings](http://www.printo.in/account/settings).

d. Forum and Blogs

Information you submit on forums, blogs, chat area or in classified areas within the Website, are accessible by public at large. Please re-consider before you submit information. Printo is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

e. Legal Disclaimer

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, subpoena, or other legal process or request to Printo brought in any country throughout the world, or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

f. Disclosures to others

We may also disclose your personal and other information you provide, to another third party as part of a reorganization or a sale of the assets of a Printo corporation division or company. Any third party to which we transfer or sell Printoï¿½s assets will have the right to continue to use the personal and other information that you provide to us.

g.Other uses:

  * Providing our products and services to users, including the display of customized content and advertising;
  * Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
  * Ensuring the technical functioning of our network; and
  * Developing new services.

**3.Your choice in managing your information**

Whenever you are submitting new posts on your Printo, please choose the visibility settings carefully. The settings so chosen are done voluntarily by you and Printo is in no way responsible for the same. Some of the changes effected in your Account settings may not be retroactive.

a. Closing your account

You can also close your account on Printo. On closure, we will remove your name and other personally identifiable information from our publicly viewable database. We may retain certain data contributed by you if we believe it may be necessary to prevent fraud or future abuse, or for legitimate business purposes, such as analysis of aggregated, non-personally identifiable data, account recovery, or if required by law. To request that we close your account and remove your information from the website, please send your request to feedback@printo.in . You will receive a response to your requests within five business days of its receipt.

b. Retrieval of information

Information provided by you including those which is set to be visible only to you is accessible by select Printo team. Printo internally has a process on information security and your information being accessed only by those who are authorised. In situations where you accidentally delete your information and would like to retrieve, then this core team may access the stored database and recover the same. Please be aware that this team may have to go through your personal information in order to restore the information sought by you.

‘

**4\. Users Obligations**

As a User, you have certain obligations toward the other Users with whom you will be communicating. Certain of these obligations are imposed by applicable law and regulations, and others have become commonplace in user-friendly communities of like-minded member.

a. You must, at all times, respect the terms and conditions of the then-current Privacy Policy and the User Agreement. This includes respecting all intellectual property rights which may belong to third parties (such as photographs).

b. You must not download or otherwise disseminate any information which may be deemed to be injurious, violent, offensive, racist or xenophobic or which may otherwise violate the purpose and spirit of Printo and its community of Users.

c. You must not provide information to Printo and /or other Users which you believe might be injurious or detrimental to your person, professional or social status.

Any violation of these guidelines may lead to the restriction, suspension or termination of your account by Printo, as we take these principles seriously and consider them to be the basis on which our Users adhere to the Printo website and the services which it offers.

**5\. Children**

Children below 14 years are not eligible to use our service and we hereby request children below this age group not to submit any personal information to us or use the service.

**6\. Information Security**

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data.

We restrict access to personal information to Printo employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

**7\. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Printo may update this privacy policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personally identifiable information, we will display a notice on the website or send you an email, as provided for above. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.

If you use the Printo service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

**Last update : September 5, 2012**
